(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T17:16:11.459476",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
世界一 可愛い
The cutest in the world,
宇宙一 可愛い
the cutest in the universe!
もっと もっと 聞かせて
Tell me more, tell me more.
ご褒美は 目を閉じて
For your reward, close your eyes.
見つけてくれて サンキュー
Thank you for finding me,
愛してくれて サンキュー
thank you for loving me.
生きがいにしちゃってもいいのよ？
Is it okay to make me your reason to live?
一人じゃ無理だっけ今日
Is it too hard to be alone today?
みんながいれば 最強
With everyone here, we're invincible!
見つめ合ってよ 思いっきり泣っちゃえ
Look at each other, let's cry our hearts out!
涙じゃなにも解決しないのはわかってるから だから
I know tears won't solve anything, so...
瞬間で一目惚れ
At a glance, love at first sight,
君はきっと運命Boy
you're surely my destined Boy.
Oh my god 眠れない夜がコンティニュー
Oh my god, sleepless nights continue.
Eye to eye 弾ける心臓
Eye to eye, a bursting heartbeat,
君がふいに近すぎて
you suddenly got way too close.
あのね 実は やっぱり いーや
Hey, actually... no, never mind,
フラれちゃうよ
I'll get rejected.
ダメだきっと 絶対 私なんて相応しくないもん
No way, surely someone like me isn't a match.
でも 抑えきれない
But I can't hold it back,
好きだよって 一言がずっと
the words "I love you"
言えなくって 泣いじゃってばっか
I keep failing to say and end up crying.
やだよ 変わりたいんだ
No, I want to change!
現状打破でLove you
Break the status quo with Love you.
残念すぎなEmotion
An emotion that's too regretful,
永続的にGood bye
say a permanent goodbye.
走り出せ パラリパラなう Yeah
Start running, para-para now, Yeah!
現状打破でLove you
Break the status quo with Love you.
感情的でIt's all right 大胆不敵 大々的に
Emotional and it's all right, fearlessly and grandly,
ねぇ 独り占めしたい Everyday Every night All night
hey, I want you all to myself, Everyday, Every night, All night.
歌ってくれてサンキュー 笑顔くれてサンキュー
Thank you for singing, thank you for smiling,
生きててよかったって 心から思った
I'm so glad from the bottom of my heart that I'm alive.
ちょっとのミスは愛嬌 だけどやる気はサイキョー
A little mistake is charming, but motivation is the strongest,
嫉妬し合って 高め合って ずっとベトベトにいこ？
jealous of each other, pushing each other, let's stay sticky together?
ずっとこのまま逃げてちゃ 愛は届かないから
If I keep running away like this, love won't reach you.
だから 何度も何度も 挑もう
That's why over and over again, I'll challenge it!
傷つき合って 高め合って ずっとベトベトにいこ？
Hurting each other, pushing each other, let's stay sticky together?
苦手をもっと逃げてちゃ 愛は届かないから
If I keep running away from weaknesses, love won't reach you.
だから 何度も何度も 挑もう
That's why over and over again, I'll challenge it!
楽しんじゃおう！
Let's just enjoy it!
現状打破でLove you
Break the status quo with Love you.
残念すぎなEmotion
An emotion that's too regretful,
永続的にGood bye
say a permanent goodbye.
走り出せ パラリパラなう Yeah
Start running, para-para now, Yeah!
現状打破でLove you
Break the status quo with Love you.
感情的でIt's all right 大胆不敵 大々的に
Emotional and it's all right, fearlessly and grandly,
ねぇ 独り占めしたい Everyday Every night All night
hey, I want you all to myself, Everyday, Every night, All night.
傷つき合って 高め合って ずっとベトベトにいこ？
Hurting each other, pushing each other, let's stay sticky together?
約束ね
It's a promise!
上手に歌えてるかな
I wonder if I'm singing well...
上手に踊れてるかな
...and if I'm dancing well.
違うの 怖くなるけど
It's different, I get scared, but
できるできるできるできる そうだ！
I can do it, I can do it, that's right!
信じてくれる人がいる
There are people who believe in me.
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
I can stay connected with you through this song.
忘れられないストーリー描いていこう
Let's draw an unforgettable story!
行くよ！
Here we go!
世界一可愛い
The cutest in the world,
宇宙一可愛い
the cutest in the universe,
もっともっと遠くへ連れてよ
take me even further away!
遠慮は見えぬ
Hesitation is out of the question,
オッケー？
okay?
瞬きも可愛い
even blinking is cute,
存在が可愛い
existence is cute!
ずっとずっと聴かせて 後生だから
Keep letting me hear it forever, I'm begging you,
目を閉じて チュッ！
close your eyes, chu!
もっともっと遠くへ連れてよ
Take me even further away,
遠慮は見えぬ
hesitation is out of the question,
オッケー？
okay?
瞬きも可愛い
even blinking is cute,
存在が可愛い
existence is cute!
ずっとずっと聴かせて 後生だから
keep letting me hear it forever, I'm begging you,
目を閉じて チュッ！
close your eyes, chu!
今日も鏡をチェック
Checking the mirror today too,
最高な笑顔届ける
delivering the best smile.
才能に甘えないの
Not relying on talent,
努力が大事だよ
effort is what matters!
ちゃんと お勉強して
Studying properly,
ちゃんとお片付けする
cleaning up properly,
時間があれば 私は最愛ドルだもん
if there's time, I'm the ultimate idol!
好きなタイプは私？
My type is me?
好きと言っても 次元が違う人
Even if you say you love me, you're from another dimension.
ピッタリの君だけど 今じゃない
You're a perfect match, but not right now.
歌う歌はもっと大人だけど 君だけのものになりたいの
The songs I sing are more grown-up, but I want to be only yours.
ああ ごめん いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Ah, sorry, please keep loving me forever, it's a promise.
わがままなお願いね
It's a selfish request,
みんなのものでいたい
I want to be everyone's.
それでも 私のこと 好きですか
Even so, do you love me?
ピンク色のフリル ふりふり すっぽり包み込んで
Pink frills, swaying and wrapping me up completely.
いつかきっとね 金色の私
Someday for sure, my golden self,
今はもっと歌いたい 現役アイドルちゅ～
now I want to sing even more, active idol chu~!
甘くて 幸せなこと
Something sweet and happy,
隠し味 何にしよう
what should the secret ingredient be?
純粋な 乙女心
A pure maiden's heart
甘い恋も絡めなくちゃ
Must weave in sweet love, too
切なさ重ねてミルフィーユ
Layering sorrow like a mille-feuille
酸味も積み上げタルト
Piling up sourness into a tart
苦味もチョコレートケーキ？
And bitterness in a chocolate cake?
魔法かけた 甘い奇跡
A sweet miracle cast with magic
甘さを抑えてビターとか
Subduing the sweetness for bitterness,
ミルクなしのコーヒーとか
Or coffee without milk,
甘いだけじゃ大人になれないの？
Can't you become an adult with just sweetness?
そんなの絶対絶対やだやだやだ
No way, absolutely no way, no way!
ねえ、あげようか 甘い罠
Hey, shall I give you a sweet trap?
ほら 餌にしてあげる
Look, I'll make you my bait
そんな魔法かけるから
I'll cast that kind of magic, so
ちょっとだけ待たせたげるわ
I'll make you wait just a little bit
たった一口が足りなくて
Just one bite isn't enough,
赤いイチゴみたい意地張って
Acting stubborn like a red strawberry
甘いところなんて見せないわ
I won't show you my sweet side
完璧に作るもん
I'll make it perfectly
一人でも、でも、でも
All by myself, but, but, but...
ねえ、気づいているんでしょ？
Hey, you've noticed, right?
わかっているんでしょ？
You understand, right?
隠し味の恋心
My secret ingredient is love
苦味とか 酸味とか
Bitterness and sourness,
そういうのもたまにはいいわ
Those are nice sometimes too
意地張りで わがままな
A stubborn and selfish
そんな「甘い魔法」使い
Such "sweet magic" user
sweetie, sweetie, sweetie, magical!
sweetie, sweetie, sweetie, yeah! yeah!
私と混ぜた人にありがとう
Thank you to the one mixed with me
こんなにキュウトな私でいちゃうもん
I'll stay this cute!
くるくるレモネードも左回ってる
The swirling lemonade spins to the left too
いつになってもこのままここで輝く
No matter when, I'll shine right here
ねぇねぇ教えて どうぞ今日も可愛い？
Hey hey, tell me, am I cute today too?
いつまでも好きでいてね ようこそだよ
Keep loving me forever, welcome!
私だって君のこと ずっとずっと大好き
I love you so, so much too
一緒に私のこと 好きですか？
Do you love me too?
ピンク色のフリフリ すっぽり包まれて
Wrapped entirely in pink frills
いつかきっとね 君だけの
Someday, surely, just for you
私に 今はまだ歌いたい
To you, I still want to sing
原石アイドルチュウ
An uncut gem idol chu!
いつまでも好きでいてね ようこそだよ
Keep loving me forever, welcome!
私だって君のこと ずっとずっと大好き
I love you so, so much too
一緒に私のこと 好きですか？
Do you love me too?
ピンク色のフリフリ すっぽり包まれて
Wrapped entirely in pink frills
いつかきっとね 君だけの
Someday, surely, just for you
私に 今はまだ歌いたい
To you, I still want to sing
原石アイドルチュウ
An uncut gem idol chu!
ピンク色のフリフリ すっぽり包まれて
Wrapped entirely in pink frills
いつかきっとね 君だけの
Someday, surely, just for you
私に 今はまだ歌いたい
To you, I still want to sing
原石アイドルチュウ
An uncut gem idol chu!
リアルアイドルチュウ
Real idol chu!
みんなー、せーの！こんばんわっしょい！
Everyone, ready? Konban Wasshoi!
どうもホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル夏色まつりでーす！
Hello, it's Hololive's pure representative, everyone's idol Natsuiro Matsuri!
ということで今年もやってまいりました！遅ばせながらの生誕誕生日祭でございますよ！
With that said, it's here once again! A belated birthday celebration festival!
まつりちゃんの誕生日、7月の22日なんでございますが、
Matsuri-chan's birthday is July 22nd, but,
まああの周年が6月ということでね、毎年11月にやらせていただいております。
well, since the anniversary is in June, we hold it every year in November.
なので今日も実質誕生日でございますね！はい、おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
So today is essentially my birthday! Yep, congratulations! Thank you so much!
そして本日のハッシュタグはこちら、どぅどぅどぅどぅ！
And today's hashtag is right here, dudududu!
夏色まつり誕生祭2025でございます！いっぱいついーとしてトレンドに入れてあげてくださいお願いします！
Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Festival 2025! Please tweet a lot and get it trending, I'm begging you!
あのスクショとかもね、あの撮っていただいたりとか、あとツイートしてくれたら、
And please take screenshots, and if you tweet them,
あのまつりちゃんがあとでエゴサさせていただきますのでぜひよろしくお願いしますね！見ちゃうよ見ちゃうよ！
Matsuri-chan will ego-search them later, so please be sure to do it! I'll be looking, I'll be looking!
はい！そしてね、まあ皆さんもお気づきかなと思います。本日のタイトル、
Yep! And well, I think you've all noticed. Today's title,
アイドル革命進行中！今日の主人公は夢の途中！というタイトルにもあるようにでございますね。
Idol Revolution in Progress! Today's protagonist is in the middle of a dream! As the title suggests.
えー、本日はアイドルさんの曲をたくさーん詰め込んだ超とってもとってもとっても可愛くてポップでキュートでワクワクするようなライブになっていますので最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！
Um, today's live is packed with tons of idol songs, super, super, super cute, pop, cute, and exciting, so please enjoy it all the way to the end!
よろしくお願いします！コメントでもサイリウムを振ったりとか「可愛いよ！」って言っちゃったりとかたくさんしてくださいね！
Please look forward to it! Please wave your penlights in the chat, or say 'You're cute!', do it a lot!
ということで、この後は皆さんお待ちかねのゲストパート、やったーー！
With that said, up next is the guest part you've all been waiting for, yay!
hey yo, D.E.M.P.A from AKIHABARA to everywhere
さあさ \u5bc4\u3063\u3066\u3089\u3063\u3057\u3083\u3044 \u898b\u3066\u3089\u3063\u3057\u3083\u3044 \u3082\u3046\u4e00\u5207\u5408\u5207\u3084\u3063\u3066\u3061\u3083\u3044\u306a
Come on in and take a look, forget about everything else!
ありったけのオトメイトと楽しいこと詰め込んで
Packed with all the cuteness and fun we could possibly fit,
さあ 少年少女よ 船に乗って いざ出航じゃ
Now, boys and girls, hop on the ship, let's set sail!
hey yo, D.E.M.P.A from JAPANESE HOT AREA
みんな元気ですか? 声聞かせて? はいでんぱー! (でんぱー!)
Are you all doing well? Let me hear your voices! Yes, denpa! (Denpa!)
ありがとさん もはや準備はバッチリのようなので (OK!)
Thanks, it looks like we're all prepped and ready to go! (OK!)
さあ 今 から でっかい 船 に 乗っ て いざ 出航 じゃ
Now, let's hop on the big ship and set sail right now!
さあ みんな ダンス ダンス ダンス わらじ履いてビラカンひらり
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance, wearing straw sandals and fluttering around,
カッコつけても パンツ パンツ パンツ はみ出てる
Looking cool, but your underwear's sticking out!
めちゃくちゃのドキュメンタリー それが僕たちにとってのファンタジー
A messy documentary, that's our fantasy,
春夏秋冬 感じるんだ 呼んでるんだ
Feeling spring, summer, autumn, winter, it's calling out to me,
あ ソレ ソレ ソレ ソレ
Ah, here we go, here we go!
シェイプ シェイプ シェイプ 胸を 張って は 汗 だら り
Shape, shape, shape, puff out your chest and break a sweat,
突っ走っても こっちこっちこっちこっち 逆方向
Running ahead, even if we go back and forth in opposite directions,
青春はそれでいいのだ
Youth is just fine that way,
勘違いも味方にしてしまうのだ
Even misjudgments turn out to be our allies!
森羅万象 歌え 日本 踊れ 日本
Embrace the universe, sing, Japan! Dance, Japan!
あ ソレ ソレ ソレ
Ah, here we go, here we go!
ちんとんてんしゃんとき どこまでも ほら パワフル全開で突き抜けろ
Step to the rhythm anywhere, full power ahead and push through,
あっちも こっちも そっち も 祭り だ わっしょい
This way and that way, it's a festival, wow!
さくら あっぱれーしょん アドベンチャー
Cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, adventure,
大和の国へ 摩訶不思議な言霊 (OK!)
An unimaginable, mysterious power of words in the land of Yamato! (OK!)
奇想天外さ いつまでも (さいさい!) 神様 仏様 兎様
Out of this world, forever and ever! (Saiai!) Gods, Buddhas, and Rabbits,
月に向けて 拝んで 君思って
Praying to the moon, bowing, thinking of you,
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off half-hearted feelings,
とりあえずいいか? 黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, is that okay? Shut up and follow me!
嗚呼 嗚呼
Whoa-oh, whoa-oh!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい
Saying we'll brightly illuminate your future is just making things up!
百花繚乱 大和撫子たちよ どでかい花火を上げましょうね
With a flurry of cherry blossoms, Yamato maidens, let's set off some huge fireworks!
ほら 踊る阿呆に見る阿呆 同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損損
Look, dancing fools and watchers are both fools, so you might as well dance!
さあ みんな ダンス ダンス ダンス さらし巻いておへそちらり
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance, let your hair down and frolic,
靴脱いだら ソックス ソックス ソックス 破れてる
Take off your shoes, socks, socks, socks are torn,
どっどばたなこのステージ
This pounding stage,
それが私にとっての正義 (ジャスティス!)
That's justice for me! (Justice!)
古今東西 羽ばたくんだ 聞こえるんだ
Past and present, fluttering about, we can hear it,
あ ソレ ソレ ソレ ソレ
Ah, here we go, here we go!
シェイク シェイク シェイク 腕を振って涙キラリ
Shake, shake, shake, wave your arms and let your tears sparkle,
強がっても きゅんきゅんきゅん 苦しいの
Pushing through even when it gets tough,
乙女はそれでいいのだ
A maiden is fine just like that,
マイナスも味方にしてしまうのだ
Even the negatives become our allies!
情意投合 愛してんだ みんな大好きだだだだだ
Pouring in all our affection, we love you and adore you all so much!
(break down)
ちんとんてんしゃんとき どこまでも (はいはい!)
Step to the rhythm anywhere, (Yes, yes!)
ほら パワフル 全開 で 突き抜けろ
Full power ahead and push through,
あっち も こっち も そっち も 祭り だ わっしょい
This way and that way, it's a festival, wow!
あっぱれ あっぱれ アドベンチャー
Cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, adventure,
大和の国へ 摩訶不思議な言霊 (それそれそれそれ!)
An unimaginable, mysterious power of words in the land of Yamato! (That's right, that's right!)
奇想天外さ いつまでも (ガッテン!) 神様 仏様 兎様
Out of this world, forever and ever! (Gotcha!) Gods, Buddhas, and Rabbits,
月に向けて 拝んで 君思って
Praying to the moon, bowing, thinking of you,
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off half-hearted feelings,
とりあえずいいか? 黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, is that okay? Shut up and follow me!
嗚呼 嗚呼
Whoa-oh, whoa-oh!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい
Saying we'll brightly illuminate your future is just making things up! (Alright!)
満月の下で 踊りましょう
Dancing under the full moon,
桜舞い散る季節と 歌いましょう
Let's sing as cherry blossoms dance and scatter in the season,
君といつか また出会う その日まで
Until the day we meet again with you,
だから 意地っ張りさんも 照れ屋さんも 八百屋さんも あなたも
So tease us, show off, be the local shopkeeper, or whoever you are,
忘れないで ばいばい さようなら (ばいばい～!)
Never forget, bye-bye, farewell! (Bye-bye!)
君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい
Saying we'll brightly illuminate your future is just making things up!
百花繚乱 大和撫子たちよ どでかい花火を上げましょうね
With a flurry of cherry blossoms, Yamato maidens, let's set off some huge fireworks!
ほら 踊る阿呆に見る阿呆 同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損損
Look, dancing fools and watchers are both fools, so you might as well dance!
さあ みんな ダンス ダンス ダンス さらし巻いておへそちらり
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance, let's roll up our sleeves and show our belly,
靴脱いでも ソックス ソックス ソックス 苦しいの
Even if our shoes tear, socks, socks, socks,
求めはそれでいいのだ
Need is something we can do without!
マイナスも味方にしてしまうのだ
Even the minus parts can be our allies!
喜びをとことん愛してた みんな大好きだだだだだ
Cherishing this joy that we love so much,
(break down)
ちんとんてんしゃんとき どこまでも (はいはい!)
Step to the rhythm anywhere, (Yes, yes!)
ほら パワフル 全開 で 突き抜けろ
Full power ahead and push through,
あっち も こっち も そっち も 祭り だ わっしょい
This way and that way, it's a festival, wow!
あっぱれ あっぱれ アドベンチャー
Cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, adventure,
大和の国へ 摩訶不思議な言霊 (それそれそれそれ!)
An unimaginable, mysterious power of words in the land of Yamato! (That's right, that's right!)
奇想天外さ いつまでも (ガッテン!) 神様 仏様 兎様
Out of this world, forever and ever! (Gotcha!) Gods, Buddhas, and Rabbits,
月に向けて 拝んで 君思って
Praying to the moon, bowing, thinking of you,
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting off half-hearted feelings,
とりあえずいいか? 黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, is that okay? Shut up and follow me!
嗚呼 嗚呼
Whoa-oh, whoa-oh!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんてお茶の子さいさいさい (ばいばい!)
Saying we'll brightly illuminate your future is just making things up! (Bye-bye!)
時間たてば事務的にやってくる
If time passes, it comes around mechanically.
明日なんて我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow.
逃げたいならどこに
If you want to run away, then where should
逃げればいいのかな
you run to? Is that okay?
曖昧な場所では何にも変われない
Nothing changes in an ambiguous place.
立ち向かうとかやり直せるよとか
Facing things head-on and doing it over,
間違った道を何度もやり直させる
or redoing a mistaken path multiple times—
あなたいったい誰ですか？
Just who are you?
論点ズレてる人達なんて押しのけて
Pushing aside people whose logic is warped,
自分の道作なくちゃ
we have to make our own path!
“失敗しない”なんて契約を人は誰とも結んではいない
"Never fail"—no one has ever made that kind of contract with anyone.
“幸せになります”とは皆いつか昔大事な人と約束したはずだ
"We'll be happy"—everyone made that promise with someone important long ago, hadn't they?
大人になるために早く忘れることだけ覚え
To become an adult, you only remember how to forget things quickly.
無理に目を背けたら10年後の自分を救えないよ
If you turn a blind eye, you won't be able to save yourself 10 years from now.
全部自分が悪いと責める君に伝えたい
I want to tell you, who blames yourself, thinking everything is your fault:
同じ言葉を人に言わない君を誰も責められない
No one can blame the person who doesn't say the same words to others.
逃げたいならどこに
If you want to run away, then where should
向かえばいいのかな
you head? Is that okay?
辛さの根源を見つめ直せる場所
A place to re-examine the source of the hardship.
いきなり空を飛ぶ方法なんて知らない
I don't even know how to fly into the sky out of nowhere.
悪と暇の行き来は誰ももうしないで！
No one goes back and forth between evil and boredom anymore, so don't!
生きろとか蘇れとかもういい
Or like, "Live or revive or whatever"—
もう逆に逃げてもいいんだよとか言う私はいったい誰ですか？
Or like, "Run away instead and it's fine"—what on earth am I? Who are you?
わかってくれてる瞳の輝きが消えてないって証明してくれた人たちがいる
The sparkle in the eyes that understand and accept us has proven that there are people.
時間たてば事務的にやってくる
If time passes, it comes around mechanically.
明日なんて我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow.
足に訊ねる走れるか
Asking your feet if you can run,
指に訊ねる開ける？
asking your fingers if you can open it,
体温に訊ねる潮で導いていけるだろうか
asking your body temperature if the tide can guide you safely.
始まりの合図は他の誰にも決めさせたくない
The starting signal is something I don't want anyone else to decide.
教科書の先の現代は我々が作っていくから
We are creating the modern age beyond textbooks!
だから逃げない
So I won't run away.
私は逃げない
I won't run away.
逃げたい君をほっといてはゆかないじゃなきゃ意味ない
If you leave the person you want to run away from alone, it has no meaning.
話し合いことない
There's no such thing as talking things through.
顔を見なくなって君を知ってる
Stop seeing their faces and knowing them.
苦しめる渦の中、頭の目広げて
Expanding the mind's eye in the swirling torment,
別の角度で見てごらん
try looking from a different angle.
そこだけ逃げないで
Don't run away from just that place.
時間たてば事務的にやってくる
If time passes, it comes around mechanically.
明日なんて我々の明日じゃない
Tomorrow isn't our tomorrow.
とくべチュ、して
Do something special for me.
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough.
一番大事がいい
The most important thing is...
君が作るオリジナルの
You create an original one.
特別、チューして。
Give me a special kiss!
まぶしくって目が覚めて
Waking up with blindingly bright eyes,
愛おしく思ってよ
Think of it with affection.
眠り姫のように優しく口付けて
Like a sleeping princess, kiss her gently.
ゴミみたいなこの世界
This trashy world...
ピュアがかる君がいる Oh Yeah!
With a pure-hearted you there, Oh Yeah!
全てに触れずに2人だけでいよう
Let's be just the two of us without touching anything.
私のこと独占して
Monopolize me,
君だけのモノになってもいい
It's fine if I become only yours.
なんでもおる日のでも何でもない、気付いてね
Notice that even ordinary days are "nothing special."
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough.
君の「特別」にして
Make it your "special."
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss もう私は 君でいっぱいよ
Hey, give me more, now I want to be filled with just you.
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon tie,
小指キュッて縛って
Tied tightly with our pinkies.
そうよ 一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want to be together forever.
とくべチュが欲しい
I want a special kiss.
2人きり週末は
Our weekend together...
奏でてよ ハーモニー
Play a harmony.
流れ星見たら私を想ってほしい
If you see a shooting star, I want you to think of me.
あまあな君なのに
Even though you're so sweet,
広い街吸い込まれ
Swallowed up by the vast city,
戦う姿に大きいはなまるだね
The bigger the fighting figure, the bigger the grade.
好きなとこら、優しいとこ。
The places you like, the places you're kind,
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ。
The places you hate, the places you're kind—
誰にもあげない 私だけ独り占め！
I won't give them to anyone, I'll monopolize you all to myself!
う〜 だって今までの人と同じはいらないんです
Ugh, because I don't need someone just like everyone up until now.
ねぇ もっと Give me more 私のため 生きてほしいんです
Hey, give me more, I want you to live for my sake.
だからウサギと私は さみしくさせないで
So, the rabbit and I, don't make me lonely.
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
That's not bondage at all,
苦しいのが好き
I like the painful kind.
ショートケーキ イチゴみたいに座ってもいい？
Can I sit like a shortcake strawberry?
赤く甘い恋だもん
It was such a sweet, red love,
誰かにあげた 大好きも 返してもらって全部私に
Someone lifted it up, so give it all back to me!
ちょーだい もっと！
Give it to me! More!
君は神様が作る 奇跡ようなヒト
You are a miraculous person created by God.
疲れた顔も その寝顔も 守ってあげるね
I'll protect your worn-out face and that sleeping expression.
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough.
君の「特別」にして
Make it your "special."
ねぇ もっと Give me a kiss もう私は 君でいっぱいよ
Hey, give me more, now I want to be filled with just you.
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon tie,
小指キュッて縛って
Tied tightly with our pinkies.
ねぇ baby 最初で最後の とくべチュにしてね
Hey baby, make it a special kiss from the very beginning to the very end.
ミルクで乾杯~ 止まったら甘い
A toast with milk~ If you stop, it's too sweet.
レンジでチンしてあったかい Let's go!
ぱぴぷぺぽ！人生万歳 この先10年安泰
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po! Long live life! Safe for the next 10 years!
盛れすぎたら半端ない Let's go!
If you get carried away, it's out of the ordinary! Let's go!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぴぴぷぴ ぴゅんぴゅん ですゆ ぴゅん でするんるん ですてきゃ ですはっぴーです
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pi-pi-pu-pi! Yun-yun, de-suyu, run-run, de-suka, desu! Happy!
問題ないは半端ない これわでいすこてぃっくなバンビな
Problems are no big deal, this is the discothique Bambi.
てきとです いーしーです あいまいです ずっとこうやって
Teki-to desu, easy desu, ambiguous desu, let's keep going like this!
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じでぽっぷにいっていこー
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, with that feeling, let's live popping!
毎日毎日本当パーリーピーポー Let me hear you dancing!
Every day is a party, Party People! Let me hear you dancing!
縦ノリ 縦ノリで 横ノリで Oh yeah!
Vertical ride, vertical ride, horizontal ride! Oh yeah!
映画のキャストみたいに ボンキュのボンボリパーティ！弾けて smile delight!
Like a movie cast, Bon-kyu Bon-bon Party! Pop it, smile delight!
なんでスレてんの？「うるさい！」なんで泣いてんの？「あっち行って！」
Why are you pouting? "Shut up!" Why are you crying? "Go away!"
ちゃらけた愛を歌ってるベイビー
Singing a playful love song, baby
煌めいてシックなメロディ
Shimmering with a chic melody
誰も見当たらない 夜がまたひとつ
No one is in sight, another night falls
頭空っぽチープなハーモニー
An empty-headed, cheap harmony
誰だって愛されたいのに
Everyone wants to be loved, yet
いらないことばかり 口をつく始末
Only needless things tumble from my lips
どうしちまったの皆 そんな顔で見んな
What's wrong with you all, looking at me like that?
まともじゃないよあなた方
You lot aren't normal either
ぱっぴぷぺぽな感じでポップにいこう
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po style, let's go pop
パピプペポ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ぱっと咲いて shy ピアニッシモで kiss
Blooming suddenly, shy, a pianissimo kiss
黒いラップよ ペプシ飲んで「あ〜」
A dark rap, drinking Pepsi like "Ah~"
ポップに踊ろう ポップに踊ろう
Dance poply, dance poply
さあLets Go Funny Funny time!
Come on, let's go, funny, funny time!
ギュンギュンです ピュンピュンです
Gyun-gyun, pyun-pyun,
ルンルンです キャッキャです
run-run, kyakka,
ハッピーです 問題ない
happy, no problem
半端ない これが我が麗し
peerless, this is our gorgeous
ディスコティックなバンビーナ
discotic bambina
テキトです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
Casual, easy, vague, keeping it up like this
なんかいい感じ もしもーし？ なんか嬉しいな
Feeling good, hello? So glad
どうした なんか なんか やっぱやっぱ 女の子だもん
What's up? Some... well, after all, we're girls
なんかハッピーです うんそれで なんか絶好調です
Feeling happy, yeah, and in top form
ああもう幸せです 聞いてよちょっと 話してだから聞いて
Ah, I'm so happy, listen to me, let me talk!
えーそうなんだ
Oh, is that so?
最高です 超絶ミラクルです 超常たがです ハイパーです
It's the best, absolute miracle, transcendent, hyper
とんでもない 異常ない これが我らアーティスティックなパッピーじゃ
Unbelievable, normal, this is our artistic puppy
ちょっとだけポンコツで 災害です ずっとこうやって
A bit clumsy, disastrous, keeping it up like this
ぱっぴぷぺぽな感じで ポップにいこう
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po style, let's go pop
ぱっぴぷぺぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po
ミルクで乾杯 砂糖混ぜたら甘い
Toast with milk, sweet when mixed with sugar
レンジでチンしてあったかい Lets go
Heated in the microwave, warm, let's go
ぱっぴぷぺぽ よー人生万歳 この先10年安泰
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, cheers to life, safe for the next 10 years
盛れればバズったらはんぱなーい Lets go
If it goes viral, it's peerless, let's go
ぱっぴぷぺぽ Poppin'!
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, Poppin'!
ぱっぴぷぺぽ ぱっぴぷぺぽ ぱっぴぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-po
愛チュセヨ Lovin' you アモーレ アミーゴ
Saranghae, Lovin' you, Amore, Amigo
ぱっぴぷぺぽ ぱっぴぷぺぽ ぱっぴぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-po
A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O People
People Be Poppin'! Poppin'! Poppin'!
最大級 最高級 最上級 ハイスペックな人生です
Maximum, highest class, top tier, high-spec life
アイラブユー アイフォーユー だけどもしも君がいないと話しな
I love you, I for you, but without you it's no use
本当はね やっぱりね 結局ね ずっとこうやって
Truly, after all, in the end, keeping it up like this
ぱっぴぷぺぽな感じでポップにいこう
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po style, let's go pop
ギュンギュンです ピュンピュンです ルンルンです キャッキャです ハッピーです
Gyun-gyun, pyun-pyun, run-run, kyakka, happy
問題ない 端ぱない これが我が麗しディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, peerless, this is our gorgeous discotic bambina
テキトです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
Casual, easy, vague, keeping it up like this
ぱっぴぷぺぽな感じでポップにいこう
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po style, let's go pop
ぱっぴぷぺぽ ポップにエンジョイ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, enjoy poply
あれこれそれどれ 楽しいね
This, that, which one, it's fun
ポジティブにコレクト ポップにエンジョイ
Positively collect, enjoy poply
あれこれそれどれ 楽しいね
This, that, which one, it's fun
ぱっぴぷぺぽ Poppin', POP!
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, Poppin', POP!
みんなゲストパートどうだった？可愛かった？ありがとうございました！
Everyone, how was the guest part? Were they cute? Thank you very much!
ということでね、すごい続けてやってしまったんですが、
So yeah, we ended up doing it back-to-back, but
まずサクラアップルイリュージョンは、あずきちとルナちゃんとリリカに出てもらいました。
first, for Sakura Apple Illusion, AZKi-chan, Luna-chan, and Ririka joined in.
なんかすごいサクラというか春っぽいね、ピンクな感じのメンバーをね、呼びました。
I called members who give off a Sakura or spring-like, pink vibe.
リリカすごいがんばったよなあ！すごいね練習中も「あ、あ、できない！」
Ririka worked so hard! Even during practice, she kept saying "Ah, ah, I can't do it!"
って言いながらね、がんばってたリリカ。
while doing her best, Ririka.
そして次、逃げないね！逃げないわ、ちょっと結構古めの曲なんですけど、まつりがすごいすごい大好きで1番推していたユルメルモさんの楽曲で、あの、ここで歌えてすごく嬉しかったです。
And next, "Nigenai"! "Nigenai" is a rather old song, but it's one Matsuri loves so much and was my absolute favorite by Yurumerumo!, so I was so happy to sing it here.
ありがとうございますね。そして特注して、は難しかった！
Thank you very much. And "Tokubetsu Shite" was hard!
すごく難しかったんだから！だってさ、1番と2番さ、あの、サビの振付も違うしさ、
It was so hard! Because, you know, verses 1 and 2, even the chorus choreography is different,
めっちゃ難しかったよ。いや、イコールラブさんの曲は毎回難しいけどすごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね。
it was super hard. Well, =LOVE's songs are always hard, but they're so fun to dance to.
はい。そして「パピプペッポップ」、これあのずっとこうやってやってるからすごい疲れて、あの、汗だくになった。
Yes. And "Pa-pi-pu-pe-Pop", since we kept doing this motion the whole time, I got so tired and drenched in sweat.
すごかったよ！練習中の時も汗だく過ぎて、「ちょっと待って！ち、ちょっと疲れた！」とか言ってね、みんなでわちゃわちゃしながらね、練習もしましたけど、すごい楽しかったでございます。
It was amazing! During practice too, I was so drenched in sweat, going "Wait a minute! I, I'm tired!" and goofing off together while practicing, but it was a lot of fun.
そしてちょっと紹介できてなかった、こちらのステージじゃーん、かわいい！すごく可愛いくね、作っていただきました。
And for the stage we couldn't introduce earlier, ta-da, look at this stage! So cute! They made it so cutely for us.
「あ、あのアイドルソングばっかりなので、アイドルのステージかっていう感じにしてください」って言ってね、こんな感じになりましたよ。
"Ah, since it's all idol songs, make it feel like an idol stage," she said, and so it turned out like this.
あのちょうちんもあるけどさ、なんかすごい、あの、主張しすぎないというかいい意味でね、あの、
There are lanterns too, but it's not too overbearing in a good way, like pastel pinks...
なんかパステルなピンクとか、まぁこれ色変わるんですけど、すごい可愛い感じにしてくれててね、
well, the colors change, but they made it look so cute,
風船もねこれね色変わるんですよ、実実はね。なんかちょっとそこらへんも注目していただきたいなと思いますね。
and the balloons change colors too, actually. I'd love for you to pay attention to that part as well.
めちゃ可愛いんですよ。あの後で1個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います。
It's super cute. I think I'll have them let me take one home later.
はい、そして、あのね、みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど、
Yes, and um, I wonder if everyone noticed,
と、あのね、まつりすがね、いるわけですよ。
um, Matsuri-su is here, you see.
そう、あのね、周年一期生の周年ライブのときにはいなかったんですよ。
Right, um, she wasn't here during the 1st generation anniversary live.
ね、エビフライオンがねいたの代わりに、
You know, instead of the ebi-fry-lion that was there,
他のさハートンとかはさ、あの、ちゃんとハートンとしていたのに、リスナーさんの姿でいたのに、祭りだけね、祭りすがいなくてエビフライオンだったんで、
the other Heartons and stuff were properly Heartons in the form of listeners, but only Matsuri wasn't Matsuri-su and was an ebi-fry-lion,
今回あの、よかったね、これって。
so I'm glad this time, isn't it?
ということで、早速続いての曲いきましょうか。
With that, let's move on to the next song right away.
続いてもうアイドルソングでございますよ。それでは聞いてください、アイドルソング。
The next one is also an idol song. So please listen, Idol Song.
例え君の顔に昔よりシワが増えても
Even if your face has more wrinkles than before,
それでもいいんだよ
that's still alright.
僕がギターを想うように弾けなくなっても
Even if I can't play the guitar the way I want to,
心の歌は君で溢れているよ
my heart is overflowing with songs for you.
高い声も出せず思い通り歌えない
I can't sing high notes or sing as I wish,
それでもうなずきながら一緒に歌ってくれるかな
but I wonder if you'll nod along and sing with me.
割れんばかりの拍手も響き渡る歓声もいらない
I don't need thunderous applause or echoing cheers.
君だけ 分かってよ 分かってよ
Just you, understand, understand.
ねぇ Darlin' 夢が叶ったの
Hey Darlin', my dream came true.
お似合いの言葉が見つからないよ
I can't find the right words.
Darlin' 夢が叶ったの
Darlin', my dream came true.
愛してる
"I love you."
君が僕を忘れてしまっても ちょっと辛いけど… それでもいいから
Even if you forget me—though it's a bit sad... that's alright too.
僕より先にどこか遠くに旅立つことは 絶対許さないから
I will never forgive you for embarking on a distant journey before me.
生まれ変わったとしても 出会い方が最悪でも
Even if we are reborn, even if our meeting was the worst,
また僕は君に恋するんだよ
I'll fall in love with you all over again.
僕の心は君にいつも片想い
My heart is always unrequitedly in love with you.
好きだよ 分かってよ 分かってよ 分かってよ
I love you, understand, understand, understand.
ねぇ Darlin' 夢が叶ったの
Hey Darlin', my dream came true.
お似合いの言葉が見つからないよ
I can't find the right words.
Darlin' 夢が叶ったの
Darlin', my dream came true.
愛が溢れていく
Love is overflowing.
ねぇ Darlin' 夢が叶ったの
Hey Darlin', my dream came true.
お似合いの言葉が見つからないよ
I can't find the right words.
Darlin' 夢が叶ったの
Darlin', my dream came true.
ねぇ Darlin'
Hey Darlin'
愛してる
"I love you."
私はからだがあるからいたい
I have a body, so it hurts,
遺体になる前に会いたい
I want to see you before I become a corpse.
私はからだがあるからいたい
I have a body, so it hurts,
私はアニメみたいになりたい
I want to be like an anime character.
瞬間最大me ピンクのサイダーみ
Maximum moment me, like pink cider,
消えてみたいな
I want to disappear,
I want to disappear.
瞬間最大me 最後の瞬間に
Maximum moment me, in the final moment,
消せなかった
I couldn't erase
自分を吐き出して
spit out the self I couldn't erase.
何次元の憂鬱で
In what dimensional melancholy,
三次元は窮窮で
the third dimension is cramped,
二次元でエスケープして
escaping into the second dimension,
一限サボって屋上から
skipping first period from the rooftop.
瞬間最大me ピンクの祭壇で
Maximum moment me, on a pink altar,
意識があって 季節もなくて
with consciousness, no seasons,
旬が過ぎて 堕ちてしまっても
past its prime, even if I fall,
恐くはない 私が選んだから
I'm not afraid, because I chose it.
君を消そうとしている世界の秘密に気づいてない
Unaware of the world's secret trying to erase you,
論理 MADE ME SO LONELY
logic MADE ME SO LONELY,
別世界なんてないからちゃんと言い話したい
there's no other world, so I want to talk properly.
CALL ME 聞かせて
CALL ME, let me hear it,
清純じゃないとダメなんて不純だろ
isn't it impure to demand purity?
悪いことしてないよ
I haven't done anything wrong.
「わかる!」って言えば
Saying "I get it!"
わっ！びっくりしたでしょ？
Whoa! Were you surprised?
今日の私が昨日より可愛いなんて！
That I'm cuter today than yesterday!
私はからだがあるからいたい
I have a body, so it hurts,
遺体になる前に会いたい
I want to see you before I become a corpse.
私はからだがあるからいたい
I have a body, so it hurts,
私はアニメみたいになりたい
I want to be like an anime character.
瞬間最大me ピンクのサイダーみ
Maximum moment me, like pink cider,
消えてみたいな
I want to disappear,
I want to disappear.
瞬間最大me 最後の瞬間に
Maximum moment me, in the final moment,
消せなかった
I couldn't erase
自分を吐き出して
spit out the self.
何次元の憂鬱で
In what dimensional melancholy,
三次元は窮窮で
the third dimension is cramped,
二次元でエスケープして
escaping into the second dimension,
一限サボって屋上から
skipping first period from the rooftop.
瞬間最大me ピンクの祭壇で
Maximum moment me, on a pink altar,
意識があって 季節もなくて
with consciousness, no seasons,
旬が過ぎて 堕ちてしまっても
past its prime, even if I fall,
恐くはない 私が選んだから
I'm not afraid, because I chose it.
君を消そうとしている世界の秘密に気づいてない
Unaware of the world's secret trying to erase you,
論理 MADE ME SO LONELY
logic MADE ME SO LONELY,
別世界なんてないからちゃんと言い話したい
There's no other world, so I want to talk properly.
CALL ME 聞かせて
CALL ME, let me hear it,
清純じゃないとダメなんて不純だろ
isn't it impure to demand purity?
悪いことしてないよ
I haven't done anything wrong.
「わかる!」って言えば
Saying "I get it!"
長いクラクションで危険を伝える勇気もない
No courage to convey danger with a long horn,
I CAN'T BE 何にも
I CAN'T BE anything,
でも惰性でここに居るわけじゃない もう少しやれそう
but I'm not here out of inertia, I can do a bit more.
LOVE LIFE DO. SO... お互い無機質で
LOVE LIFE DO. SO... both inorganic,
いつでもさよならできたとしても
even if we could say goodbye anytime.
ねえYOU HATE YOU 「いいね!」っていえば
Hey YOU HATE YOU, saying "Likes!"
満たされる意味はない
has no fulfilling meaning,
思考停止 やめて
stop thinking like that.
私はからだがあるからいたい 遺体になる前に会いたい
I have a body, so it hurts. I want to meet you before I become a corpse.
私はからだがあるからいたい 私はアニメになれない
I have a body, so it hurts. I cannot become an anime.
私があなたを知ることと あなたが私を知ることと
Me knowing you, and you knowing me,
悲しみに触れることと 愛で触れ合うことが希望
touching sadness, and touching with love is hope.
何歳になっても可愛いねじゃないの！
Don't just say "you're cute no matter how old you are"!
こっちだって努力して可愛いやってんの！
I'm working hard to be cute over here!
何十何歳だったらかわいいの本音はそんなの当たり前だもん！
Of course being cute in your tens or twenties is normal!
言わせないでよ！
Don't make me say it!
そっちが言って！
You say it!
今日も可愛いねでしょ？今日も可愛いね！
You should say "You're so cute today too" right? "You're cute today too!"
キミに恋な恋の息をずっと
Falling in love with you, the breath of love forever,
胸が苦しいんです
my chest aches so much.
早くレスキュー速期の
Quickly, rescue, fast telepathy,
速期のテレパシーに早く気づいて
realize the fast telepathy quickly!
SOS
初めて出会ったときから
Ever since the first time we met,
ハートが震えてたんだよ
my heart has been trembling.
無意識に意識しちゃうこの感じは片想いだって
Unconsciously getting conscious of you, feeling like it's unrequited love,
求め合うだけで顔が熱いの
just wanting each other makes my face hot,
話しかけられて頭がパニック
being spoken to makes my head panic.
Being spoken to makes my head panic.
ドキドキし,
With a heart full of excitement...
ドキドキを響かせよう 最高な時間 最高な仲間と
Let's make our heartbeat echo, with the best time and the best friends!
キラメキに乘って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
導かれたような出会い
A guided encounter...
目と目が合った瞬間に
at the exact moment our eyes met,
イタズラに運命さえ変えてしまいたい
we wanted to playfully change even fate itself.
友達のままで終わりそうにない夏
A summer that feels like it will never end as friends.
暑さが増す
The heat increases...
蝉の鳴音と窓際の鳴らない風鈴
the cicadas' chirping and the wind chime by the window that doesn't ring.
そんな季節に君に出会った
I met you in such a season.
期待外れな場所へと風を送る扇風機
An electric fan blowing wind to an unexpected place.
会いたいんだよ…今君に
I want to see you now...
にちもさちもいかなくて
feeling nervous and restless,
君に電話をかけたけど最後の一歩踏み込めないまま
I tried calling you, but I couldn't take that final step.
導かれたような出会い
A guided encounter...
目と目が合った瞬間に
at the exact moment our eyes met,
イタズラに運命さえ変えてしまいたい
we wanted to playfully change even fate itself.
友達のままで終わらせたくない夏
A summer we don't want to end just as friends.
画用紙みたいな青い空と
A blue sky like drawing paper...
絵の具で描いたような雲
and clouds painted with paints.
そのちょっと下で君を待つ
I wait for you just below them.
少し遅れて着いた君は暑そうに顔をしかめて
You arrived a little late, pulling a long face from the heat,
「待たせたね」とすぐに笑う
and immediately smiled, saying, "Sorry to keep you waiting."
にちもさちもいかないのは二人の会話
Being nervous and restless is just our conversation.
わかってる 好きだと言わなきゃ進めないのは
I know it—if I don't say "I like you," I can't move forward.
夏の海に上がる花火 全てを覆うように
Fireworks rising over the summer sea, as if to cover everything.
不意に聞こえてきた「好き」 君の口から
Unintentionally, I heard a "I like you" from your lips.
二人の世界が今交わりあった
Our worlds intersected just now.
導かれたような出会い
A guided encounter...
手と手が触れた瞬間に
the moment our hands touched,
イタズラに笑い合って 二人の世界重なった
we smiled at each other playfully, overlapping our worlds.
友達のままで終わりそうにない夏
A summer we don't want to end just as friends.
ドキドキし,
With a heart full of excitement...
ドキドキを響かせよう 最高な時間 最高な仲間と
Let's make our heartbeat echo, with the best time and the best friends!
キラメキに乘って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
覚えてるかな？
Do you remember?
最初の歌（懐かしいね）
Our first song (nostalgic, huh?),
私声が震えていた（ほんの少し）
my voice was trembling (just a little).
あの日から続く未来は
The future that continues from that day...
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
is today that we grasped together with everyone!
もっともっともっともっと加速するハート
More, more, more, more, accelerating heart!
（いっしょに）行くよどこまでも
(Together) Let's go anywhere!
（are you ready?）準備はok？
(Are you ready?) Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ！！ 夢のトビラを（123）
Open wide! The door of dreams (1, 2, 3)!
（キラメキ ライダー☆）
(Sparkle Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our heartbeat echo from when we were born,
最高な時間 最高な仲間と
with the best time and the best friends.
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We are here because you found us,
きみに会いたくて やってきたんだよ
because we wanted to see you so badly we came here!
みんなで歌おう
Let's sing together,
終わらない メロディ
a never-ending melody,
キラメキに乘って☆
riding on the sparkle☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our heartbeats resonate with the thrill of being born!
最高な時間 最高な仲間と
The best time, with the best friends.
キラメキに乘って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
覚えているかな？ 最初の歌（懐かしいね）
Do you remember? Our first song...
私声が震えていた（ほんの少し）
my voice was trembling just a little.
あの日から続く未来は みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
The future continuing from that day is today we grabbed together!
もっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
More, more, more, accelerating heart!
（いっしょに）行くよどこまでも （are you ready?）
Let's go anywhere together! (Are you ready?)
準備はok？ ひらけ！！ 夢のトビラを
Is your preparation OK? Open wide the door of dreams!
覚えているかな？最初の歌
Do you remember? Our first song...
私声が震えていた
my voice was trembling just a little.
あの日から続く未来は みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
The future continuing from that day is today we grabbed together!
もっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
More, more, more, accelerating heart!
（いっしょに）行くよどこまでも （are you ready?）
Let's go anywhere together! (Are you ready?)
準備はok？ひらけ！！ 夢のトビラを
Is your preparation OK? Open wide the door of dreams!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our heartbeats resonate with the thrill of being born!
最高な時間 最高な仲間と
The best time, with the best friends.
キラメキに乘って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
重さねた手はきっと離さずに
The hands we reached out shouldn't be let go so easily.
一人違う描き出すときめき
Alone, we're different, but let's draw and create our sparkling future.
振り向くことなくてもすぐに
Turning around, spinning around without stopping, right away!
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the sky where dreams are seen!
重さねた手はきっと離さずに
The hands we reached out shouldn't be let go so easily.
一人違う描き出すときめき
Alone, we're different, but let's draw and create our sparkling future.
振り向くことなくてもすぐに
Turning around, spinning around without stopping, right away!
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the sky where dreams are seen!
笑い合ったことや 月並みじゃないわたし
Laughter and tears, times when we couldn't keep up,
思い出いっぱいななに 上書きじゃなくて
memories full of them, day after day, without overwriting them!
いつも間にか見つけていた遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I knew it,
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
Scenery I couldn't see all on my own.
波打つ風の音と
With the sound of rippling winds,
加速していく思いに戸惑いを覚えた
and accelerating feelings, I felt confused.
ずっと追いかけた理想の姿はまだ届かなくて遠いけど
The ideal self I've always chased is still far away,
きっとこの瞬間をかけがえないみんなで共に行くよ！
let's go together with everyone in this irreplaceable moment!
手をつないで
Holding hands,
3・2・1！
3, 2, 1!
輝き宿して
Hosting our radiance,
夢の場所へ！
heading to the place of dreams!
駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は誰にも止められないよ！
The light of our youth running through can never be stopped!
笑い合う分だけ（優しく）
As much as we laugh together (so gently),
零れる涙さえ（今）ほら輝かせ
even the spilling tears (now) look, let them shine,
明日へ運ぶから 君のお隣へ
carrying them to tomorrow, right by your side.
僕たちは世界を超えていく 迎えに行くよ
We'll go beyond the world, and come to greet you,
まだ見えない明日も キラメキに変えて
transforming even the unseen tomorrow into glitter,
きっと僕たちが未来へと 連れて行くから！
and for sure, we'll lead you onward to the future!
背伸びして手を伸ばす 憧れの行方示す星になろう
Standing on tiptoes and reaching out, let's be stars pointing to our yearnings.
つまずくその度に手を差し伸べ合えたら すぐに届くはずさ
Whenever we stumble, if we reach out our hands, we'll surely reach it right away.
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気が
The small courage we gently stepped forward with
もう消えないように繋げよう
Let's connect it so it never fades away.
不安も愛しさも 大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both anxiety and affection dearly,
共に行くよ！
Let's go together!
目を合わせて
Meeting each other's eyes,
3・2・1！
3, 2, 1!
晴れ渡る希望へ
Toward clear-skied hopes,
飛び出せるよ！
We can leap out!
突き抜けていく僕たちの透き通る決意は
Our clear determination breaking through
まだまだ止められないよ！
Can still not be stopped!
ありきたりな今日こそ キラメキに変えてもっと
Turning even ordinary days into glitter more and more,
僕たちがいつでも 背中押すから！
We will always push you from behind!
ずっと一人で描いていたキャンバスが いつからかコライトになって
The canvas I've always drawn alone somehow became a co-creation,
また少しずつ芽生える大好きを紡ぎ
Spinning the growing love little by little,
どこまでも高く あすいろの空へ
Higher than anywhere else, to the asuiro sky.
駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は 誰にも止められないよ！
The light of our youth running through can never be stopped by anyone!
零れる涙さえ今ほら輝かせ
Even the spilling tears, now look, let them shine,
明日へ運ぶから君のお隣へ
carrying them to tomorrow, right by your side.
僕たちは世界を超えていく 迎えに行くよ
We'll go beyond the world, and come to greet you,
まだ見えない明日も キラメキに変えて
transforming even the unseen tomorrow into glitter,
きっと僕たちが未来へと 連れて行くから！
and for sure, we'll lead you onward to the future!
同じ未来を見たい あの夢を手にしたい
I want to see the same future, hold that dream in my hands,
それぞれ違った心で 走れgo
With our different hearts, run, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えた
In a pitch-black place, sprouting
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were stolen by just a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my trembling, anxious heart,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字でいいとして進む苦しい時も
Even in painful times when giving up seemed easier,
もう私は一人じゃないから
I'm no longer alone anymore.
だからもっと夢追いかけたい わくわく止まらない
That's why I want to chase my dreams more, excitement won't stop.
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world beyond imagination.
アクセスしてみたい 後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, I won't let you have any regrets.
それぞれ違った心で 走れgo
With our different hearts, run, go!
仮想の空に輝くまぶしい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
Deliver an unseen light to reality.
いつも聞こえるエールをここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers we always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
Makes me want to search for new light.
君の笑顔は保存して進む 悲しい時に見返すよ
Saving your smile as I move forward, to look back on when I'm sad.
力湧くから 胸を張って夢追いかけたい
Because strength wells up, I want to proudly chase my dreams.
奇跡のストーリー 一緒に作ろう 終わらない夢を
Let's create a miraculous story together, an endless dream.
はい、ということで
Yes, so,
ホロライブ、に、ホロライブメル…ねえ、自分の事務所なのに！
Hololive... wait, Hololive Me... hey, even though it's my own agency!
あ、でして。
Ah, um.
え、どうだった？ なんか劇エモ…だったんじゃないですか？
So, how was it? Wasn't it super emotional?
そしてね、この衣装は初めてもらったアイドル衣装なんですけど、なんかあの当時を思い出して、なんかすごいしーんときてしまいますわね。
And you know, this outfit is the first idol outfit I ever received, so remembering those days makes me feel all choked up.
そう、まつりはね、元々そのアイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよ、ホロライブって。で、この衣装をもらって、よし、アイドルとして頑張るぞというね、気持ちを改めて思い出し、がんばっていくかなという気持ちでございます。
That's right, Matsuri wasn't originally supposed to debut as an idol in Hololive. But receiving this outfit made me renew my feelings of 'Alright, I'll do my best as an idol!' and I want to keep working hard with that feeling.
はい、そしてそして、今回も…誕生日グッズでちゃいまーす！やったー！うれしー！
Yes, and and, this time too... birthday merch is coming out! Yay! I'm so happy!
まずは、こちら！どどーん。
First up, is this! Tada!
薄すぎ！？おっぱいマウスパッド！あ、おっぱいマウスパッド！やったー！イラストはえく先生！
Too thin!? Oppai mouse pad! Ah, oppai mouse pad! Yay! Illustrated by Eku-sensei!
マツリス待望のね、マウスパッドでございますよ。
It's the mouse pad Matsurisu have been waiting for.
もう、あの、ちなみに言うと、ふくらみは、ないです。普通のマウスパッドとなっております。
Now, um, by the way, there is no swelling. It's just a regular mouse pad.
ね、こうやってあの癒やすことはね、ちょっと難しいんですが、
You know, it's a bit hard to make people feel healed like this,
ちょっとガチ照れな、キュンみたいな感じなのでね、
but it's like super bashful and makes your heart flutter,
あの、もう心から癒されていくという感じで、はい、どうですか？素晴らしいグッズでございましょう。
so, you know, it's meant to heal you right from the heart. So, how's that? Aren't these wonderful goods?
そして続いて、こちら！
And next up, we have this!
じゃーん！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Tada! A random acrylic keyholder!
なんと、夏色まつり先生のね、描き下ろしでございますよ！
It features brand-new illustrations drawn by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei herself!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー。
Random acrylic keyholders.
まつりがね、グッズのイラスト描くって、なかなか無いですから、
Since it's pretty rare for Matsuri to draw her own merchandise illustrations,
すごい愛着を込めて描きました。もう、ちゅちゅちゅちゅってしながら描いたので、
I drew them with so much affection. I drew them while going "mwah mwah mwah,"
ぜひね、全種類コンプリートしてみてくださーい！
so please try to collect all of them!
そして、続いてこちら！
And moving on to this!
まつりぬいぐるみ サブカルジャージ衣装Ver.でございます！
The Matsuri plushie in her subculture jersey version!
キービジュのね、イラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装のなんと、ぬいぐるみが登場しちゃいますよ！
The plushie wearing the exact same subculture jersey outfit from the key visual is finally here!
キービジュのように、おしくらおすことはちょっと現実だと叶わないけど、
You can't actually squish together with her like in the key visual in real life,
ぬいぐるみなら、ぬいぐるみならできちゃうということで、
but with a plushie, with a plushie you can do it!
ぜひね、たくさんかわいがって、色んなとこに連れて行ってあげてください。
So please shower her with love and take her everywhere with you.
さらにこちら！ まつりすマグカップ！
And even more! The Matsurisu mug cup!
みんなにはマグカップになってもらいました。どんな罪を犯してこんな姿になっちまったんだ！って感じではございますが、
Everyone got turned into a mug cup. I'm like, "What kind of sins did you commit to end up looking like this?!"
ま、自分なのでね、あの、これが俺の姿か！と思いながら使っていただけたらなと、まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます。
Well, since it's me, I hope you'll use it thinking, "So this is what I look like!" I'll be using one too, Matsuri-chan style.
最後に、ボイス！じゃじゃーん！
And lastly, voices! Tada!
シチュエーションボイス「逆襲のまつりす」。
Situation voice: "The Counterattack of Matsurisu."
なんた、逆襲のまつりすなんだ？
What's "The Counterattack of Matsurisu"?
はい、今回ね、キービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーがここに詰まっちゃってますので、どんなシチュエーションなのかちょっと気になる方はぜひゲットしてみてください！
Yes, this time the story leading up to the key visual's situation is packed right in here, so if you're curious about what kind of situation it is, please go get it!
フルセットをご購入いただいた方全員に直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきちゃいます！
Everyone who purchases the full set will receive a postcard with a handwritten autograph and hot-stamped duplicate message!
え、ちょっとね、来年は直筆やるかちょっとまだ未定でございますので、ぜひね、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、
Um, as for whether I'll do handwritten autographs next year, it's still undecided, so please, please, please, please,
全員に書かせていただきますので、初めてなんです、それも。全員にサイン書くの初めてだから、
I'll write them for everyone. It's actually my first time doing this too. It's my first time writing autographs for everyone,
ぜひ手に入れてください！来年やるかかんないからね。
so please get your hands on it! Who knows if I'll do it next year.
さらにですね、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、2024年9月から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてきちゃいますよ！
Furthermore, as a full set bonus for talent premium goods, you'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game released in September 2024!
まつりはね、前回のグッズでちょっと特典につかなかったので、今回ついてくるよって感じになっております。
Since Matsuri wasn't included as a bonus in the previous merchandise, she's included this time around.
え、同封する、同封であってる？日本語。はい、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップでご購入されたお客様のおにょにょ、
Um, included, is "included" correct? My Japanese. Yes, for customers who purchased at the Hololive Production Official Shop, um,
お客さまの
exclusively for customers
のみ対象となっておりますので、よろしくお願いします！特典につくのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用でき推しをアピールできるキーカード、
who are eligible, thank you very much! The bonus is a key card that can be used once in the game to show off your oshi,
推しホロメンカードでございます。
the Oshi Holomem card.
そしてそしてそしてさらにでございますよ！まだある！アルバム！
And and and even more! There's more! An album!
ててててててて！なんとまつりちゃん、ファーストアルバム「Chasing the Dream ～スポットライトは放課後に～」がなんと、本日11月1日に受注開始でございます！ぱんぱくぱーん！
Ta-da! Matsuri-chan's 1st album "Chasing the Dream ~Spotlight wa Houkago ni~" is available for pre-order starting today, November 1st! Yay!
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲「君と眺める夏の花」を始め、これまでに配信リリースしてきた作品のほか、じんさん始め豪華作編曲家さんが書き下ろしてくださった新曲楽曲も収録しちゃってますよ！計14曲の超ボリュームのアルバムになっているのでぜひ手に入れちゃってください！
Starting with Matsuri-chan's very first original song "Kimi to Nagameru Natsu no Hana," along with previously released tracks, it also includes brand-new songs written by amazing composers and arrangers like Jin-san! It's a massive album with a total of 14 tracks, so please be sure to get your hands on it!
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんのこう両面みたいな、両方が楽しめるようなね、アルバムになってます。
The concept is an album where you can enjoy both sides of Matsuri-chan: the idol Matsuri-chan and the ordinary high school girl Matsuri-chan.
形態は2つありまして、完全生産限定盤と通常盤をご用意しております。
There are two editions available: the Complete Production Limited Edition and the Regular Edition.
完全生産限定盤はですね、セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーがついてきちゃいますよ！
The Complete Production Limited Edition comes with a separate-type original calendar!
そして、両形態に封入特典として、夏色まつりからのお手紙（複製）が入っています。
And both editions include a duplicated letter from Natsuiro Matsuri as an enclosure bonus.
ただし、数量限定のランダムでですね、複製お手紙のかわりに直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が封入されていますので、ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください！
However, as a limited-quantity random bonus, instead of the duplicated letter, instructions on how to receive a genuinely handwritten letter are included, so please be sure to get your hands on it!
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album info!
そしてなんと！アルバムに収録する新曲のうち
And what's more, this is one of the new songs
1曲なんですね。
included on the album!
本日、このあと
Today, right after this,
披露しちゃいます！
we'll be releasing it!
タイトルは
The title is...
ウーニャカーニャニャニャン！
"Oo-Nyaka-Nyanya-Nyan"!
作詞作曲はですね、かいりきベアさんに
The song was written and composed by
作詞していただきました！めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
Kairiki Bear, and it's so, so cute!
MVもですね、このあとプレミア公開ありますので、え、0時から
The MV will also premiere after this at 12:00 AM,
あの、楽曲リリースもありますので、
along with the song release,
あの、ぜひよろしくお願いしますね。
so I hope you'll check it out!
プレ、プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね！はい！
Let's all watch the premiere together!
じゃあ、ちょっと着替えてきますので、ちょっとここで待ってて、「わくわく」って言いながらね、あのゲストパートと同じように「わくわく」って言いながら待っててください。
So I'm going to go get ready, so please wait here while saying "Waku-waku" just like the guest part!
じゃあ行ってきまーす！
Well then, I'm going!
わくわく！わくわく！
Waku-waku! Waku-waku!
真夜中にトケタ 感情は爪立てて
In the dead of night, feelings melt and bare their claws,
カゴから見慣れた 世界は牙向いて
The world seen from a cage bares its teeth.
真夜中見かねた 感情は飢えた目で
In the dead of night, emotions look on with starving eyes,
軽やかに逃げた 優しさ求めて
Lightly escaping, searching for a gentle touch.
「愛されたい」の想い 愛されないのGive me
The desire to be "loved," but missing out with a "Give me."
「愛してる」も重い？愛されないの？もういい？
Is "I love you" too heavy? Can't even be loved? Is that enough?
愛情結晶頂戴 あなたを見ているのにゃ
The crystallization of love, I'm worthy of it—I'm watching you, nya.
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyannyaka, rinrinrin, a plea.
さあ手懐けてよ もっとめいっぱい
Come closer, give me all your affection!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おでかけ？
Nyannyaka, rinrin, rin, going out?
しがみついて 何処も行かせない！
Clinging on, I won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン 甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve sweet candy!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン ハッピー ライフ頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve a happy life!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン 叱らないで頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I shouldn't be cast aside!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve true "love"!
縄張り土足で 感情目丸くして
With bound feet, making my feelings round and bright,
幸せになれた 未来が牙向いて 突き放さないでいて 切り捨てず傍で
The future where I could be happy bares its teeth—don't thrust me away, stay close by my side!
お傍で お傍で 見ているのにゃ
By my side, by my side, watching you, nya.
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねがい
Nyannyaka, rinrinrin, a plea.
さあ頭撫でて もっとぜーいっぱい
Pat my head, give me even more!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おあずけ？
Nyannyaka, rinrin, rin, missing out?
甘えて泣いて 此処に居させて！
Let me stay right here, acting spoiled and crying!
ニャンニャカ 言ったって 伝わらない？
Even if I say nyannyaka, it doesn't get across?
どーしたってこーしたって 寂しいの
No matter what, no matter what, I'm so lonely.
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おもいっきり あざとい声 わざと聞かせる
Nyannyaka, rinrinrin, purposely making my voice sound cute.
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyannyaka, rinrinrin, a plea.
さあ手懐けてよ もっとめいっぱい
Come closer, give me all your affection!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おやすみ？
Nyannyaka, rinrin, rin, going to sleep?
しがみついて 今夜寝かせない！
Clinging on, I won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン 甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve sweet candy!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve a happy life!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン 抱きしめて頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve a warm embrace!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウー ニャンニャン ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Oo-nyaka, nyannya, oo-nyanya, I deserve true "love"!